Guide to the Carroll L. V. Meeks Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Carroll L. V. Meeks papers
1928-1966
MS 706
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
18
(33 boxes, 1 folio)
The major portion of the papers consists of research materials for a study of the architecture of Yale University; research materials on Connecticut architecture, railroad stations, and Works Progress Administration files for Connecticut; and research for Carroll Meeks's book on Italian architecture, published in 1966. Included in the materials on Yale are photographs, articles, manuscripts, notes and bibliographies. Additional papers reflect Meeks's teaching career at Yale University (1930-1966) and his membership in organizations dedicated to architectural preservation. His correspondence includes letters from a number of notable art historians. Prominent among the correspondents are James Ackerman, Turpin C. Bannister, Kingman Brewster, James Marston Fitch, Siegfried Giedion, Maynard Mack, Denis Mack Smith, Lewis Mumford, Richard Neutra, Robert Rosenblum, Paul Rudolph, Vincent Scully, Sir John N. Summerson, Christopher Tunnard, and Rudolf Wittkower.
Meeks, Carroll L. V. (Carroll Louis Vanderslice), 1907-1966
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Box 33, student evaluations, is restricted as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
Arrangement
Collection has been inventoried as received, and includes two accessions.
Scope and Contents
The Carroll L. V. Meeks Papers consist of eighteen linear feet of correspondence, research material, photographs, and miscellaneous papers relating to Meeks's career as a Yale professor and historian of architecture. They have been minimally processed and are roughly organized by subject as received from the donor. The following is an outline of the materials: Papers related to Yale buildings and grounds (boxes 1-4); Additional papers related to Yale architecture and to Italian architecture, but less organized (boxes 5-16); Card files containing notes on Italian architecture (boxes 17-26); Mounted photographs of Street Hall, Yale University (box 27, which has been transferred to the Yale Picture Collection); Files containing professional correspondence and miscellaneous papers arranged alphabetically by subject or correspondent (boxes 28-32); Papers related to evaluation of students' work (box 33, which is closed to researchers); Printed articles, primarily in Italian, on art and architecture (box 34, a folio)
Meeks's research material on the architecture of railroad stations, which was in the Slides and Photograph Collection, was transferred to Manuscripts and Archives, SML, in 1991.
Biographical / Historical
Carroll Louis Vanderslice Meeks was born in Bridgeport, Connecticut on May 21, 1907. He received his Ph.B. degree from Yale University in 1928, his B.F.A. in 1931, and his M.A. in 1934. Meeks earned a Ph.D. from Harvard in 1948. He was a member of the Yale faculty from 1930 until his death on August 27, 1966.
Architecture -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Architecture, Italian; Art historians; Educators; Historians; Ackerman, James S., 1919-2016; Bannister, Turpin C. (Turpin Chambers), 1904-1982; Brewster, Kingman, Jr., 1919-1988; Fitch, James Marston; Giedion, S. (Sigfried), 1888-1968; Mack Smith, Denis, 1920-2017; Mack, Maynard, 1909-2001; Meeks, Carroll L. V. (Carroll Louis Vanderslice), 1907-1966; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990; Neutra, Richard Joseph, 1892-1970; Rosenblum, Robert, 1927-; Rudolph, Paul, 1918-1997; Scully, Vincent, Jr., 1920-2017; Summerson, John, 1904-1992; Tunnard, Christopher, 1910-1979; Wittkower, Rudolf; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. School of Art and Architecture
- Inventory, [1930s-1966?]; 18 linear feet (33 boxes, 1 folio)
  Scope and Contents
  Note: Folders marked "empty" contain no material but may be used for future accessions (April 2007).
  - Old Campus, General (18th, 19th, 20th Century) (Box 1)
  - Yale Guides, General (Box 1)
  - Possible sources of Yale buildings (Box 1)
  - Surveys of Yale Architecture, General (Box 1)
  - 18th Century, General (Box 1)
  - Rector's, or First President's House (west side of College Street just below Chapel Street sold by Yale in 1801) 1722-1799 (Box 1)
  - Connecticut Hall (Old South Middle on the Old Campus Brick Row) 1752 (Box 1)
  - Old Laboratory or First Commons (Old Campus) 1782-1888 (Box 1)
  - Union Hall (Later called South College, Old Campus) 1793-1794/1893 (Box 1)
  - Second President's House (for Dwight and Day, present site of Farnam Hall, 380 College Street) 1799/1800-1846 (Box 1)
  - First Chapel or Athenaeum (Old Campus) 1761/1763-1893 (Box 1)
  - Yale History, General (Box 1)
  - Professor of Divinity House (York Street, site of Medical School Building) 1757/1758 (Box 1)
  - The Faculty Club (originally the John Pierpont House, 149 Elm Street) 1764/1767 (Box 1)
  - Fraternities and Societies General (18th, 19th, 20th centuries) (Box 1)
  - The Residential Colleges (General) (Box 1)
  - "Yale College", First Building (Chapel and College Streets on site of Bingham Hall) 1717/1718-1782 (Box 1)
  - Yale Medical School (Box 1)
  - Views of Yale, General (Box 1)
  - Plans and Maps of Yale, General (Box 1)
  - 19th Century, General (Box 2)
  - Berkeley Hall (North Middle College, Old Campus) 1801-1895 (Box 2)
  - Connecticut Lyceum (Old Campus) 18-3/04-1901 (Box 2)
  - Silliman House (built for James Hillhouse, moved in sections 1871-1877 to Trumbull Street and Davenport Avenue, sold to Yale 1920, 1926) 1807 (Box 2)
  - The Elizabethan Club (purchased in 1911, 459 College Street) 1810/1815. [empty] (Box 2)
  - (South) Sheffield Hall (on site on Sheffield-Sterling-Strathcona Hall) (purchased 1814) 1931 (Box 2)
  - Philosophical Building (also known as the Cabinet, on the Old Campus) 1819-1890 (Box 2)
  - North College (Old Campus) 1820-1901 (Box 2)
  - Second Chapel (Old Campus) 1823/24-96 (Box 2)
  - Secondary Commons (no. 63 High Street on site of Chittenden Hall, called Yale Club in 1879) 1827- (Box 2)
  - Woodyard 1830's (Box 2)
  - Trumbull Gallery (Old Campus) 1831/32-1901 (later used as the Treasury Building 1868, Administrative Offices for Department of Music 1890-1901.) (Box 2)
  - Sheffield Mansion (6 Hillhouse Avenue, on site of Dunham Laboratory Addition) c. 1832-1957 (Box 2)
  - First Divinity School (or Divinity College) 1835-1869 (Box 2)
  - College Street Hall (on site of Loew-Poli College Theater, purchased in 1895, sold in 1917) - 1921 (Box 2)
  - Hopkins Hall (formerly Hopkins Grammar School; on site of Sterling Law Buildings) 1840 (purchased 1913) - 1930 (Box 2)
  - Dwight Hall (Old Library, now contains Dwight Memorial Chapel) 1842-1846 (Box 2)
  - 52 Hillhouse Avenue (house of Professor Norton, purchased by University in 1923, now the Economic Growth Center) 1849 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Hall (originally called Graduates Hall, on site of Wright Hall, Old Campus) 1851/1853-1911 (Box 2)
  - First Beta Theta Pi (a tomb) 1850 (Box 2)
  - Skull and Bones Hall (64 High Street) 1856 (enlarged in 1883 and 1903) (Box 2)
  - The First Yale Boat House (on Mill River above Grand Street Bridge) 1859 (Box 2)
  - First Gymnasium, Dining Hall 1892-1901, Herrick Hall 1902-1917, on Library Street) 1859-1917 (Box 2)
  - Second Medical Building (150 York Street) 1859/1860-1957 (Box 2)
  - First Delta Kappa Epsilon (tomb on site of Memorial Quadrangle) 1861 (Box 2)
  - Second Yale Boat House 1863 (Box 2)
  - Scroll and Key Hall (484 College Street) 1869 (Box 2)
  - Street Hall (1071 Chapel Street)1864/1866 (Box 2)
  - Farnam Hall (Old Campus) 1869 (Box 2)
  - Durfee Hall 1869/1871 (Old Campus) (Box 2)
  - Marquand Chapel (on site of Calhoun College) 1871-1931 (Box 2)
  - Second Divinity School (or East Divinity Hall, renamed Edwards Hall) on the site of Calhoun College. 1869/1870-1931 (Box 2)
  - First Fence Club (founded as Beta chapter of Psi Epsilon on site of Sterling Library) 1970 (Box 2)
  - The President's House (originally the Henry Farnam House, 43 Hillhouse Avenue) 1871 (Box 2)
  - First Delta Kappa Epsilon (second Tomb) 1872 (Box 2)
  - North Sheffield Hall (45 Prospect Street) 1872/1873 (Box 2)
  - Old Peabody Museum (on site of Saybrook College) 1873/1876-1917 (Box 2)
  - Second Divinity Hall (or West Divinity Hall addition to Second Divinity School, on site of Calhoun College, renamed Taylor Hall 1909) 1873-1931. [empty] (Box 2)
  - Battell Chapel (corner of College and Elm Streets) 1874-1876 (Box 2)
  - Third Yale Boat House (Yale boat house on New Haven Harbor off Chapel Street) 1874/1875-1910 (Box 2)
  - Marsh Hall (build as residence for Professor Garden, later converted to Marsh Botanical Garden, 360 Prospect Street) 1878 (Box 2)
  - First Berzelius Tomb (west side of Prospect above Trumbull Street, later Alpha Sigma Hall) c. 1880-1930 (Box 2)
  - Trowbridge Library (on site of Calhoun College) 1881-1931. [empty] (Box 2)
  - Yale Observatory (135 Prospect Street, addition in 1956) 1882-1883 (Box 2)
  - First Sloan Physics Laboratory (later called Sloan Lecture Hall, on Library Street) 1882/1883-1931 (Box 2)
  - Henry Barbard Hall (28 Hillhouse Avenue, built as residence for Charles Farnam, purchased by University in 1920) 1884. [empty] (Box 2)
  - Dwight Hall (Old Campus) 1885/1886-1926 (Box 2)
  - Lawrence Hall (Old Campus) 1885/1886 (Box 2)
  - Kent Chemical Laboratory (on site of Jonathan Edwards College) 1887/1888-1931 (Box 2)
  - #1 Hillhouse Avenue (formerly Cloister Hall, Book and Snake Society) 1888 (Box 2)
  - Osborn Hall (on site of Bingham Hall, Old Campus) 1888-1926 (Box 2)
  - Chittendon Hall (63 High Street) 1888-1890 (Box 2)
  - First Zeta Psi 1890-1891 (Box 2)
  - Third Gymnasium (University Gymnasium, on site of Trumbull College Dining Hall) 1890/1829-1932 (Box 2)
  - Winchester Hall (15 Prospect Street-Street) 1892 (Box 2)
  - Welch Hall (Old Campus) 1892 (Box 2)
  - 111 Prospect Street (formerly 38 Hillhouse Avenue house for Henry F. English, now Under-Graduate Admissions and Scholarships Office) 1892. [empty] (Box 2)
  - First Psychological Laboratory (Elm Street at Porter Gateway, sold to Yale 1892) 1900. [empty] (Box 2)
  - Yale Infirmary (276 Prospect Street) 1892 (Box 2)
  - Vanderbilt Hall (Old Campus) 1893/1894 (Box 2)
  - Boiler House and Steam Department (1893-1917) on site of Branford College. [empty] (Box 2)
  - White Hall (on site of Berkeley College, use as dormitory and offices for Phi Beta Kappa, Yale-In-China) 1893/1894-1933 (Box 2)
  - Berkeley Hall (Berkeley Oval, on site of Berkeley College) 1893/1894-1933 (Box 2)
  - First Saint Anthony Hall (on present site, 483 College Street) 1894 (Box 2)
  - Sheffield Laboratory of Engineering Mechanics (Sheffield Chemical Laboratory, 51 Prospect Street) 1894/1895 (Box 2)
  - No. 15 Hillhouse Avenue (built for Alpha Delta Phi, sold to University 1930, Yale Collection of Musical Instruments) 1894/1895 (Box 2)
  - Gibbs Hall (125 High Street, sold to Yale 1895) 1932. [empty] (Box 2)
  - First Saint Elmo Hall (founded as Delta Phi) 1895 (Box 2)
  - Hendrie Hall (Old Law School, used briefly by the Divinity School and as a Drama Annex, 165 Elm Street) 1895 (Box 2)
  - Pierson Hall (on site of Wrexham Tower, Memorial Quadrangle) 1896-1917 (Box 2)
  - Phelps Hall and Archway (344 College Street, Old Campus) 1896 (Box 2)
  - Stoeckel Hall (formerly York Hall of the Chi Phi Fraternity, 96 Wall Street) 1897 (Box 2)
  - The Colony (dormitory of Berzelius Society, 17 Hillhouse Avenue) 1898 (Box 2)
  - Second Zeta Psi (site of Sterling Memorial Library) 1898/1899 (Box 2)
  - Old Music School (on site of Sprague Memorial Hall, formerly the home of President Timothy Dwight, the younger [1899 acquired 1916]) (Box 2)
  - The Memorial Quadrangle (Harkness Memorial Tower, Branford College Chapel, Wrexham Tower Branford College, and Saybrook College) 1920-1912 (Box 3)
  - Round House (205 Elm Street) 1900-1933. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Fayerweather Hall (on site of Berkeley College) 1900/1901-1933 (Box 3)
  - Bicentennial Buildings (including the University Dining Hall, or Commons, formerly the Old Gym, Woolsey Hall, and Memorial Hall) 1901/1902 (Box 3)
  - Second Psychological Laboratory (295 York Street) -1901 (Box 3)
  - Jane Ellen Hope Memorial Building (321 Congress Avenue) 1901. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Woodbridge Hall (105 Wall Street) 1901 (Box 3)
  - Second Book and Snake (214 Grove Street) 1901 (Box 3)
  - Kirtland Hall (2 Hillhouse Avenue) 1902 (Box 3)
  - Phi Gamma Delta First Tomb (new at site of Helen Hadley Hall) 1902 (Box 3)
  - Lampson Lyceum and Hall, (on site of Berkeley College) 1903-1933 (Box 3)
  - Byers Hall (now part of Silliman College, 505 College Street) 1903 (Box 3)
  - Vander built - Scientific Halls (now part of Silliman College) 1903-1906 (Box 3)
  - Hammond Metallurgical Laboratory (14 Mansfield Street) 1904 (Box 3)
  - Gales Ferry Hoat House (Gales Ferry, Connecticut) purchase and gift to University 1905, additions in 1926-1927) 1905 (Box 3)
  - 370 Temple Street (built as Vernon Hall for Phi Gamma Delta, sold to University 1934) 1906 (Box 3)
  - Lingly Hall (adjoining Chittenden Hall) 63 High Street 1906/1907 (Box 3)
  - Sachem Hall (built for Phi Sigma Kappa, purchased by Yale 1934, sold to Berkeley School 1940, renamed Brewster Hall) 1907 (Box 3)
  - Leet Oliver Memorial Hall (12 Hillhouse Avenue) 1908 (Box 3)
  - Carnegie Swimming pool (1909-1932) Elm Street behind Old University Gymnasium on site of Trumbull College Courtyard (Box 3)
  - Haughton Hall (on site of Berkeley College, offices for Bursar, Glee Club, Yale Record, Bureau of Appointments) 1909-1933 (Box 3)
  - Berzelius Tomb (76 Trumbull Street) 1910-1930's (Box 3)
  - Fourth Yale Boat House (Adee Boat House, East Bank of Mill River, sold 1958) 1909/1910 (Box 3)
  - 451 College Street (formerly 119 College Street, Theta Xi Fraternity or Franklin Hall, later call alumni Hall) 1910-1911 (Box 3)
  - Mason Laboratory Of Mechanical Engineering (9 Hillhouse Avenue) 1911 (Box 3)
  - Wright Hall (Old Campus) 1911/1912 (Box 3)
  - Day Missons Library (between East and West Divinity Halls on site of Calhoun College) 1911-1931 (Box 3)
  - Elihu Club Inc. Building (175 Elm Street, originally a Tory Tavern) 1911 purchased (Box 3)
  - Second Sloan Physics Laboratory (217 Prospect Street) 1912 (Box 3)
  - Dunham Laboratory of Electrical Engineering (10 Hillhouse Avenue) 1912 (Box 3)
  - Second Saint Elmo Hall (formerly as Delta Phi, now Yale Foreign Language Laboratory) 1912.purchased 1962 (Box 3)
  - Osborn Memorial Laboratories (165 Prospect Street) 1913 (Box 3)
  - 493 College Street (formerly 137) - (originally built for Delta Psi purchased by University in 1945), 1913. (Box 3)
  - Second Saint Anthony Hall (483 College Street) 1913 (Box 3)
  - Pierson-Sage Boiler and Refrigeration Plant (Kline Science Center) 1913. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Yale Bowl (251 Derby Avenue) 1914 (Box 3)
  - Second Beta Theta Pi (at 124 High Street on present location of Sterling Memorial Library 1916/1916. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Yale Armory (70 Central Avenue) 1917 (Box 3)
  - Artillery Hall (on site of Sterling Memorial Library) 1917-1927. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Albert Arnold Sprague Memorial Hall (470 College Street, 98 Wall Street) 1917 (Box 3)
  - Anthony N. Brady Memorial Laboratory (310 Cedar Street) 1917 (Box 3)
  - 143 Elm Street (the Governor Ingersoll House, purchased by Yale University Press, 1918) 1831 1918 (Box 3)
  - Nathan Smith Hall (62 Park Street) 1918 acquired 1956 sold and demolished; 1918-1919 Chemical Welfare Laboratory; 1919-1923 Laboratory; 1924-1956 Nurse's dormitory (Box 3)
  - University Heating and Power Plant and University Service Bureaus Building (20 Ashmun Street) 1918 (Box 3)
  - University Chaplains-Residence (66 Wall Street, or 326 Temple Street, built for residence of John Lynde 1806, acquired by University 1919) 1919. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Faculty Club (149 Elm Street, built as residence for John Pierpont, 1764-1767, purchased by University 1921) 1921 (Box 3)
  - First Health Department building (On site of present Building at 435 College Street.) 1921, purchased 1929 (Box 3)
  - Alumni House (built as residence for John Hart Lynde, sold to Yale 1922 turned over to alumni 1953, 320 Temple Street) 1806 (Box 3)
  - Sterling Chemistry Laboratory (225 Prospect Street) 1922/1923 (Box 3)
  - Peabody Museum of Natural History (170 Whitney Avenue) 1923/1924 (including Bingham Oceanographic Laboratory Addition in 1959) (Box 3)
  - Lapham Field House (255 Derby Avenue, West Haven) 1923 (Box 3)
  - Sterling Power House (309 Congress Avenue) 1923/1924. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Fifth Yale Boat House (the Bob Cook Boathouse in Derby, Connecticut) 1924 (Box 3)
  - Weir Hall (66 High Street) 1924 (Box 3)
  - Second Wolf's Head (210 York Street) 1924 (Box 3)
  - Sterling Hall of Medicine (333 Cedar Street) [empty] (Box 3)
  - Sage Hall (205 Prospect Street) 1924 (Box 3)
  - Edwin McCellan Hall (old Campus) 1925 (Box 3)
  - The University Theatre (222 York Street) 1925/1926 (Box 3)
  - Beta Theta Pi (Third House at read of 204 York Street) 1926/1927 (Box 3)
  - William L. Harkness Hall (100 Wall Street) 1927 (Box 3)
  - Charles E. Coke Memorial Gymnasium (Coxe Cage, at Yale Field, 257 Derby Avenue, West Haven) 1927 (Box 3)
  - The University News Building (built by the Yale Record Office, 254 York Street) 1928 (Box 3)
  - Old Art Gallery (56 High Street) 1928 (Box 3)
  - Walter Camp Memorial Gateway (251 Derby Avenue, West Haven, Connecticut) 1927/1928 (Box 3)
  - Lauder Hall (310 Cedar Street) 1928 and Farnam Memorial Building (789 Howard Street) 1928 [empty] (Box 3)
  - Second Fence Club (founded as the Beta Chapter of Phi Epsilon) 244 York Street 1928 (Box 3)
  - Third Zeta Psi (212 York Street) 1929 (Box 3)
  - Charles W. Bingham Hall (Old Campus) 1928 (Box 3)
  - International Student Center Office (211 Park street, built for Chi Psi Fraternity, sold to University 1960) 1929 (Box 3)
  - Institute of Human Relations (333 Cedar Street) 1929/1930 (Box 3)
  - Laboratory for Medicine and Pediatrics (789 Howard Avenue) 1929/1930 [empty] (Box 3)
  - Second Delta Kappa Epsilon (232 York Street) 1930 (Box 3)
  - Second Health Department Building (Department of University Health, 435 College Street) 1930 (Box 3)
  - Drama Annex (205 Park Street, built for Alpha Chi Rho Fraternity) 1930. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Second Phi Gamma Delta (Vernon Hall) 217 Park Street) 1930-1931 [empty] (Box 3)
  - Trumbull College (241 Elm Street) 1929/1933 (Box 3)
  - Sterling Law Building (127 Wall Street) 1931 (Box 3)
  - 215 Park Street (built for Alpha Delta Phi) 1931 (Box 3)
  - Bowers Hall (205 Prospect Street) 1931. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Briton Hadden Memorial Building (for the Yale Daily News Office, 202 York Street) 1932. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Sheffield Hall, Sterling Tower, and Strathcona Hall (corner Grove and Prospect Streets) 193 (Box 3)
  - Third Divinity School (the Sterling Divinity Quadrangle) 1932 (Marquand Chapel, Day Missions Library, and Trowbridge Reference Library) (Box 3)
  - Jonathan Edwards College (70 High Street) (including Dickenson and Wheelock Halls 1925/1926 1932 (Box 3)
  - Calhoun College (189 Elm Street) 1932 (Box 3)
  - The Mouse House (309 Congress Avenue) 1933. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Pierson College (231 Park Street) 1931 (Box 3)
  - Hall of Graduate Studies (320 York Street) 1932 (Box 3)
  - Davenport College (248 York Street) 1933 (Box 3)
  - Timothy Dwight College (345 Temple Street) 1934 (Box 3)
  - Berkeley College (205 Elm Street) 1934 (Box 3)
  - No. 27 Hillhouse Avenue (built for G.P. Fisher, sold to Yale 1935) 1866. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Silliman College (503 College Street) 1940 (Box 3)
  - New Art Gallery (111 Chapel Street) 1953 (Box 3)
  - The Accelerator Laboratories (51 Sachem Street) 1943/1955. [empty] (Box 3)
  - No. 30 Hillhouse Avenue (built for E.S. Wheeler purchased by Yale 1954, Cowles Foundation 1955) 1884. [empty] (Box 3)
  - Fourth Gymnasium (Payne Whitney Gymnasium, Tower Parkway) 1932 (Box 3)
  - 47 Hillhouse Avenue (built in 1862 [for Prof. James Mason Hoppin], later home of Pres. James Rowland Angell), 1923 (sold to University) - 1941 (Box 3)
  - Coxe Cage (Box 4)
  - Hockey Arena (Box 4)
  - William Harkness Hall (Box 4)
  - Keith, E. D. and Warren, W. L.: "Peter Banner, His Building Speculations in New Haven" (Box 4)
  - Henry Austin (1804-1891); Old Library; 24 and 52 Hillhouse Ave. ...[empty] (Box 4)
  - Henry Caner (c. 1679-1731); "Yale College," First President's House (Box 4)
  - Josiah Willard Gibbs Research Laboratories (51 Sachem Street) 1955 (Box 4)
  - Edward S. Harkness Memorial Hall (1 South Street, Dormitories for the Yale School of Medicine) 1955 (Box 4)
  - 295-297 Crown Street (purchased by University 1956-1957). [empty] (Box 4)
  - Hunter Radiation Therapy Center (60 Davenport Avenue, part of the Yale Medical School and Grace New Haven Community Hospital) 1957-1958 (Box 4)
  - Helen Hadley Hall (420 Temple Street). 1958 (Box 4)
  - David S. Ingalls Rink (for Hockey, 73 Sachem Street) 1958 (Box 4)
  - William B. Greeley Memorial Laboratory (370 Prospect Street) 1959 (Box 4)
  - York-Crown Apartments (purchased 1959 by University for married student housing) 1959. [empty] (Box 4)
  - Yale University Press Building (purchased and remodeled by University in 1959-1960, 149 York Street) 1959-1960. [empty] (Box 4)
  - 254 Prospect Street (purchased by University 1960). [empty] (Box 4)
  - Ezra Stiles and Samuel F.B. Morse Colleges (302-304 York Street) 1960-1962 (Box 4)
  - Mansfield Street Apartments (291-311 Mansfield Street) 1961. [empty] (Box 4)
  - Yale Computer Center (60 Sachem Street) 1961 (Box 4)
  - Beinecke Rare Book Library 1961-1963 (Box 4)
  - 24 Hillhouse Avenue (the Dana House built in 1849, purchased by University in 1962 for Department of Statistics,) 1962. [empty] (Box 4)
  - Esplanade Apartments (386 Prospect Street Housing for married students, purchased by University 1962) 1962. [empty] (Box 4)
  - Art and Architecture Building 1963 (Box 4)
  - Kline Science Center (including Kline Geology Laboratory, Kline Chemistry Laboratory, Kline Biology Tower) 1963-1965 (Box 4)
  - Nuclear Structures Laboratory (51 Sachem Street) 1964. [empty] (Box 4)
  - Laboratory of Epidemiology and Public Health (60 College Street) 1964. [empty] (Box 4)
  - Laboratory of Clinical Investigation (School of Medicine) 1965. [empty] (Box 4)
  - Peter Banner (FL. 1794-1828); 2nd House Berkeley Hall or North College, Connecticut Lyceum [empty] (Box 4)
  - Commons was gymnasium 1859 (Box 4)
  - New Haven, Yale (Box 4)
  - Graduates Club 1800 (Box 4)
  - Tombs and Fraternities (Box 4)
  - Club House, Yale Field, 1900 (Box 4)
  - "John Trumbull and the Brickrow", Yale Library Gazette. (Box 4)
  - Plans of 89 Trumbull Street. [empty] (Box 4)
  - Yale News Building; Briton-Hadden Memorial (Box 4)
  - Noah Webster (Box 4)
  - Architecture, Department of Yale University, twenty-fifth year (Box 4)
  - Bowers Areas (Box 4)
  - Mansfield Street Apartments (Rudolph) (Box 4)
  - Observatory (Box 4)
  - Correspondence and Notes Architecture Drawings (Box 4)
  - Yale University. Universities and their Sons. Its History, Influence equipment and Characters. (BOOK) (Box 4)
  - Yale Architecture and Yale Art School (Box 5)
  - "Yale, General" (file) (Box 5)
  - "Yale Guides" (file) (Box 5)
  - Yale Architecture (includes photostats of articles on architecture under President Griswold (Box 6)
  - Italian Architecture (Box 7–13)
  - Italian Architecture (Box 14)
  - Yale Architecture: miscellaneous information on locations of drawings at Yale of Yale Architecture (as of 1966) (Box 14)
  - Italian Architecture (Box 15–16)
  - Card files: notes on Italian Architecture (Box 17–26)
  - Mounted photographs of Street Hall: exteriors, interiors and plans
    Separated Materials